manhattanprep.com 2019-01-26

# Privacy - Manhattan Prep

**PRIVACY POLICY**

This privacy policy explains how MG Prep, Inc. (“Manhattan Prep”) uses, shares and protects personal information that we collect, including on manhattanprep.com (“Site”). By visiting the Site or purchasing, enrolling in or using our products, services, workshops and events (collectively, “Programs”), you agree to this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into the Terms and Conditions. _Site is intended for U.S. residents. If you are a resident of the European Union, please visit the site of our affiliated company at[manhattanprep.co.uk.](http://manhattanprep.co.uk/)_

**Information We Collect** We collect information that you voluntarily provide to us, including personally identifying information such as your name, postal address, e-mail address, SMS or text message address, phone number, educational background, and credit card information (“Personal Data”). We collect Personal Data from you in various ways, including when you visit the Site, create an account with us, purchase, enroll in and use our Programs, use our Apps, answer surveys, participate in our social media communities, such as on Facebook, and when you send us feedback. 

When you log-on to our websites or to our App(s), we automatically receive information from your device, including your IP address and location. We and our service providers may use “cookies” to keep, and sometimes track, information about you, and to create a personalized web experience. Cookies are small data files that are stored on your device’s web browser. Cookies track where you travel on our Site and what you look at and purchase. You agree to the use of cookies in this way. Most web browsers can be set to inform you when a cookie has been sent to you and provide you with the opportunity to refuse that cookie. We and our service providers may also use so-called “pixel tags”, “web beacons”, “clear GIFs” or similar means (collectively, “Pixel Tags”) in connection with some Site pages and HTML-formatted email messages to, among other things, compile aggregate statistics about Site usage and response rates. A Pixel Tag is an electronic image, often a single pixel (1×1), that is ordinarily not visible to Site visitors and may be associated with cookies on the visitors’ hard drives. Pixel Tags allow us to count users who have visited certain pages of the Site, to deliver branded services, and to target our promotional or advertising campaigns and determine their effectiveness.

If your parent, school, employer or other third party purchases Programs on your behalf, such third parties may provide us with personal data about you. We may also collect Personal Data about you from our business partners and other Manhattan Prep affiliates, subsidiaries and parent companies, including Kaplan, Inc. (“Kaplan”).

**Use of Your Personal Data** We may use your Personal Data in the following ways: 

  * For the purpose you provided personal data, for example to enroll you in one of our Programs or respond to a specific inquiry; 
  * To customize and personalize your learning experience to you;
  * To administer, support, improve and develop our business; 
  * To send you information about Kaplan and Manhattan Prep products or services;
  * To send you information about select third party’s products or services that may be of interest to you;
  * To allow you access to the Site to post your content or communicate with others; and
  * And as otherwise described to you at the point of collection.

**Mobile Devices, Phone Calls & SMS** If you provide Manhattan Prep with a telephone number, such as when you purchase, enroll in or use a Manhattan Prep Program, you agree that Manhattan Prep may contact you by telephone and/or text message utilizing automated technology at such telephone number(s). You understand that this consent is not required to purchase goods or services from Manhattan Prep. 

**Disclosure of Your Personal Data** We do not share your Personal Data with third parties for their marketing purposes, though we may share your Personal Data with other Kaplan companies. We may disclose your Personal Data in response to legal process, to protect our rights, as otherwise required by law, or for the prevention or detection of a crime. We may share your Personal Data with trusted third parties who are delivering services to Manhattan Prep, including those who help deliver our Programs, help us process transactions, such as charging your credit card when you make purchases, and otherwise help us operate our business. These third parties are not authorized by us to use your Personal Data except in connection with providing services to us. Manhattan Prep may disclose anonymous data with third parties. We may also share your information with third parties that you have specifically designated as authorized to receive information from us. 

If payment for your Program was made by a third party or if you are a student or prospective student of an institution that contracted with Manhattan Prep to provide you with the Program, that third party or institution may request access to your data. For example, if Manhattan Prep provides You access to a Program in your capacity as a student of a school that has contracted with Manhattan Prep, then Manhattan Prep may share your personal data with your school, even if you paid for the Program in whole or in part yourself. 

If we sell our company or part of it, or our business enters into a joint venture with another business entity, we may disclose your Personal Data to our new business partners or owners who may then provide you with information about their products and services. 

**Transfer of Data Outside of Your Home Country** Your Personal Data will be held in the United States. Your Personal Data may also be stored, processed and accessed in other countries where Manhattan Prep has facilities or where you are located. You consent to the transfer of your Personal Data outside your country, including to the United States. 

**Security & Information Retention** We employ security measures to protect your information both online and offline from access by unauthorized persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage. The Personal Data we obtain from students allows Manhattan Prep to deliver smarter, more efficient and more effective instruction. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy** We will update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the “Effective Date” at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you check our Site(s) from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in this Privacy Policy or any of our other policies. 

**Contact** All comments, queries and requests relating to this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed as follows: 

By mail: Kaplan Inc. 750 Third Avenue, 7th Floor, New York, NY 10017

By phone: 800- 527-8378

By fax: 800-878-4364

By email: ktplegaldept@kaplan.com
